<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An Account of the taking the late Earl of Argyle, and the running away of the rebels in Scotland</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1685</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75745</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A405</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R211819</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">38875497</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 38875497</idno>
            <idno type="VID">152160</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75745)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 152160)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2281:5)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An Account of the taking the late Earl of Argyle, and the running away of the rebels in Scotland</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Thomas Newcomb, in the Savoy,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1685.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Published by authority"</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Argyll, Archibald Campbell, --  Earl of, 1629-1685.</term>
               <term>Scotland --  History --  1660-1688.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:152160:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>An Account of the Taking the Late Earl of <hi>ARGYLE,</hi> and the Running away of the Rebels <hi>in SCOTLAND.</hi>
            </head>
            <argument>
               <p>Publiſhed by Authority.</p>
            </argument>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Whitehall, <date>June 22.</date> at Nine in the Morning.</dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>SInce the Account we received yeſterday from <hi>Scotland,</hi> which is already made Publick in the <hi>Gazette,</hi> a Flying Pacquet ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rived this Morning with Letters Dated at <hi>Edenburg</hi> the 19th Inſtant, at Ten in the Forenoon, with this further Account.</p>
            <p>The Earl of <hi>Dumbarton,</hi> Commander in Chief of his Majeſties Forces in <hi>Scotland,</hi> having notice that the Rebels had paſſed the Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver <hi>Levin</hi> above <hi>Dumbarton,</hi> Marched from <hi>Glaſcow</hi> the Seventeenth very early in the Morning after them, they taking their way to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards <hi>Sterling,</hi> and overtook them in the Pariſh of <hi>Killerne;</hi> The Horſe and Dragoons kept up the Rebels till the Foot arrived, but they were Poſted in ſo ſtrong a Ground, and it was ſo late in the Evening, that it was not thought fit then to Attack them, ſo the Kings Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my ſtood in Battle all Night, to be ready ſo ſoon as Day-Light ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peared, to fall upon them, but the Rebels with great ſilence Marched off in the Night towards the River <hi>Clyde,</hi> which they Swam with their Horſe, and carried over their Foot in Boats near a Village cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>Kilpatricke,</hi> and ſo got without much reſiſtance into <hi>Renfrew.</hi> The Kings Army miſſing the Rebels in the Morning, Marched with all diligence to <hi>Glaſcow,</hi> where, after they had reſted two Hours, the Earl of <hi>Dumbarton</hi> with the Horſe and Dragoons Marched after them, leaving the Foot to follow with all the haſte they could make, but ſoon after he received Intelligence, That the Rebels were Running away in great Confuſion.</p>
            <p>The ſame day (being the 18th) about ſeven at night, three Servants belonging to Gentlemen of <hi>Renfrew,</hi> found the late Earl of <hi>Argyle</hi> running away with a Bonnet on his Head, endeavouring to get towards the Ford of <hi>Clyde</hi> at <hi>Inchennan;</hi> He refuſed at firſt to tell his Name, or to render himſelf, whereupon they Wounded him, and would have Killed him; but that he told them he was the Earl of <hi>Argyle;</hi> Then they took him and brought him to their Commander the Lord <hi>Cochran,</hi> who carried him Priſoner to <hi>Glaſcow</hi> to the Earl of <hi>Winton,</hi> who Commands there, and who ſent this Relation to His Majeſties Privy Council at <hi>Edenburgh.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>Tho. Newcomb,</hi> in the <hi>Savoy,</hi> 1685.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:152160:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
